PIERRE GUINOISEAU

Site Reliability Engineer

contact

summary

pierre@guinoiseau.nz +64 29 126 7846 linkedin://pierreguinoiseau

I'm a 32 years old Frenchman in New Zealand with 12+ years experience as a Linux/Unix systems engineer, Site Reliability Engineer / DevOps engineer and Go, Python, Ruby developer. I'm looking for my next adventure!

languages

experience

French: native English: fluent Spanish: notions Te Reo Māori: learning

Go, Python, ♥ Ruby

2018–2020 **Magic Leap**

Wellington, New Zealand

programming Magic

Maori. learning Lead Site Reliability Engineer

Magic Leap is an American startup company that released a head-mounted virtual retinal display, called Magic Leap One, which superimposes 3D computer-generated imagery over real world objects.

Remote position with a globally distributed SRE team supporting Magic Leap's customer services.

- improved and maintained a CI platform based on Concourse CI and Hashicorp Vault using Terraform;
- main contributor to an internal build tool written in Go wrapping Terraform operations and more:
- maintained a dozen custom Terraform providers and hundreds of Terraform modules;
- migrated most Terraform modules and dozens of projects from Terraform 0.11 to 0.12;
- focused on cost savings and avoiding/killing technical debt;
- learned Go programming to an advanced level.

2015-2018 Catalyst IT

Wellington, New Zealand

DevOps engineer / PHP and Python developer

Catalyst IT is a global team of skilled open source technologists, specializing in developing, designing and supporting enterprise grade systems using open source technologies.

DevOps engineer in the eLearning team, delivering, customizing and hosting Moodle and Totara LMS sites for schools, universities, corporations and government organisations.

- built and maintained a CI platform and deployment tools around GoCD and Ansible:
- maintained the Moodle sites hosting infrastructure in the Catalyst Cloud based on OpenStack;
- backend development on some Moodle sites;
- web development on PaCT (Progress and Consistency Tool), built with Django.

Linux/Unix systems engineer / DevOps engineer

M6 Web is the M6 Group's subsidiary responsible for developing websites for TV channels, Catch-up TV, VOD, thematic web portals, comparison shopping websites, and more.

Linux/Unix Systems engineer in a small team working together with a remote ops team.

- designed, build and maintained the hosting infrastructure, spread across 2 datacenters and AWS for a total of 400+ physical and virtual heterogeneous hosts hosting 150+ websites and webservices;
- migrated a huge SVN repository into hundreds of Git repositories;
- built a CI platform using Jenkins and Docker, together with a homegrown centralized deployment solution built around Capistrano and a custom REST API using Grape and Sidekiq.

2008–2010 Pilot Systems

Lvon & Paris, France (remote work)

Python/Zope/Plone developer and Linux/Unix system administrator

Pilot Systems is an Open Source Integrator, specializing in Python solutions, like Zope, Plone, Django, etc.

Fully remote position with a team based in Paris developing and maintaining intranet and extranet solutions for several customers.

- developed and maintained Zope/Plone applications;
- maintained and migrated a major French newspaper's website;
- maintained and modernised the hosting infrastructure based on Xen.

2007–2008 **Eliot** Voiron, France

Web developer and embedded system developer — Part-time internship

Eliot designs and produces modular on-board telematic Solutions for transport (goods and passenger), logistics and industrial companies.

Student intern position in a small team.

- developed an API around a proprietary mapping, routing and geocoding server (deCarta DDS) that could be used in a backoffice software;
- tested a next-generation on-board terminal running Embedded Linux OS on an ARM platform.

education

2007–2008 **Bachelor's Degree** in Computer Science Université Pierre Mendès-France (Grenoble II) Licence professionnelle "Systèmes Informatiques et Logiciels" (Information Systems and Softwares)

2005–2007 **Associate's Degree** in Computer Science Université Pierre Mendès-France (Grenoble II)

DUT Informatique (Higher National Diploma in Technology / Computer Science)

skills

• **Programming languages:** Go, Python, ♥ Ruby

• Operating systems: Linux (Gentoo, Debian, Ubuntu, RedHat), ♥ FreeBSD, OpenBSD

• Cloud computing platforms: AWS, GCP

• Virtualization: VMWare ESX(i), Xen

• Infrastructure as Code: CloudFormation, Terraform

• Containerization: Docker

• Configuration management: Puppet + MCollective, Chef, Ansible

• CI: ♥ Gitlab CI, Bitbucket Pipelines, Concourse, Jenkins, GoCD

• SCM platforms: ♥ GitLab, GitHub, Bitbucket

• **Logging, monitoring:** Datadog, Sentry, SumoLogic, Prometheus, StatsD+Graphite+Grafana, Cacti, Nagios/Icinga

interests

Playing guitar, drumming, photography, longboarding, hiking, martial arts, sharing craft beers with my friends.